Gauray Upadhyay

Telangana, India | +91 9933315128 | gauravu644@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gaurav-upadhyay-ba78a5247

Profile Summary

Curious and driven Computer Science student with experience in MERN stack, web scraping, and AI. Applies systems thinking and first-principles problem-solving to develop innovative digital solutions. Excels in frontend development, automation, and data analysis.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Java, C

Web Development: MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) Tools & Concepts: Git, Figma, Web Scraping, UX/UI, DevOps basics

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Critical Thinking, Active Listening, Problem Solving

Experience

Frontend Developer Intern - Deep Thought EdTech | Hyderabad | Jun 2023 - Feb 2024

- Contributed to DT HUB and DT Thon platform UI/UX
- Designed onboarding flow (NUX) with team
- Collaborated with developers and designers

Data Science Intern - Unique Biotech Ltd. | Telangana | Mar 2024 - Nov 2024

- Scraped and organized B2B client data
- Created structured lead databases
- Scheduled meetings and supported Expo outreach

Projects

Herbal Life Hub

A platform to explore medicinal plants with details like plant family, properties, cultivation methods, and direct Amazon links.

GitHub: https://github.com/GAURAV-UPADHYAY-1010/herballife_hub_2.5

Live: https://herballife-hub-2-5.vercel.app/index.html

Common Disease Catalog

A website listing common diseases with symptoms and remedies in a catalog format. Built using HTML/CSS and deployed on Vercel.

GitHub: https://github.com/GAURAV-UPADHYAY-

1010/common_disease/blob/main/catalog.html

Live: https://commondisease-git-main-gaurav-upadhyay-1010s-

projects.vercel.app/catalog.html

T Paryavaran (Environment Awareness Platform)

A project aimed at promoting environmental awareness with educational content and engaging UI.

GitHub: https://github.com/GAURAV-UPADHYAY-1010/Paryavaran

Live: https://paryavaran1-git-main-gaurav-upadhyay-1010s-projects.vercel.app

Achievements

- Scored 99% in MERN Stack Project Showcase
- 1st Prize Intercollege Hackathon @ Annamacharya Institute
- 2nd Round Qualifier Stanley College Hackathon
- 3rd Prize Hackathon @ St. Mary's Group of Institutions

Education

B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering (CSE), St. Mary's Engineering College, JNTUH | 2022 – Present (3rd Year)

High School - CSE (CBSE), BSF Senior Secondary School, West Bengal | 66% | 2020 – 2022 ICSE - CSE, St. Alphonse School, West Bengal | 84% | 2010 – 2020

Workshops

Design Thinking, Systems Thinking, Lateral Thinking, Leadership, Emotional Intelligence